Guide to the Bernhard Eduard Fernow papers, 1885-1930.
Fernow, Bernhard Eduard papers, 1885-1930.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bernhard Eduard Fernow papers, 1885-1930.
20-1-561
Bernhard Eduard Fernow, 1851-1923.
2.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Newspapers, Publications, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes manuscripts, speeches and articles by Fernow concerning forestry.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Bernhard Fernow was Chief of the Division of Forestry, U.S. Department of Agriculture (1886-1898), and Director of the New York State College of Forestry at Cornell University (1898-1903).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes manuscripts of speeches and articles by Fernow concerning forestry, forest legislation, and the Division of Forestry, U.S. Department of Agriculture; letters concerning the history of forestry and forest legislation in the United States; correspondence related to Fernow's position at Cornell, with J. Sterling Morton, U.S. Secretary of Agriculture, with commercial firms in the United States and Germany, and with the New York State Forest, Fish and Game Commission; scrapbooks of clippings concerning forestry, the College of Forestry at Cornell, artificial rain making, and Fernow himself; corrected printer's proof of his book ECONOMICS OF FORESTRY; and family correspondence. Also includes correspondence between Fernow and Captain Ahern, head of the Philippine forestry service, concerning the recruitment of foresters to serve under Ahern, and including remarks on the alleged mismanagement of Philippine forests by the Spanish, 1900-1902.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fernow, Bernhard Eduard, 1851-1923.; Ahern, Captain; Fernow, Bernhard Eduard. Economics of forestry.; Morton, J. Sterling.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York (State). Forest, Fish and Game Commission; New York State College of Forestry.; United States. Department of Agriculture. Division of Forestry.
Subjects:
Forests and forestry--Law and legislation.; Forests and forestry--History.; Forests and forestry--Philippines.; Rain-making.; Foresters.
Places:
Philippines.; Germany.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Alphabetical Correspondence, 1895-1921
  - General correspondence A-N, 1895-1921 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Bu, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Ca - Ci, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Ch - Cl, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Co, excluding Collins, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - letters to Thomas W. Collins, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Cr - Cu, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Da - De, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Collins to Fernow, re: Demonstration Forest, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Collins to Fernow, re: Demonstration Forest, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Di - Dr, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Du, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Ea - Em, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - En - Ex, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Fa - Fi, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence- Fisher, predominantly Wager Fisher, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Fl - Fu, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - Ga - Ge, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Gi, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Go - Gu, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - Ha, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - He - Hi, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Ho, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence - Hu, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - I-J, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence -Ke - Ki, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence - Kl - Kn, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence - Ko - Ku, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - La - Le, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence - Li - Ly, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - Ma - Mac, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence - Man - Mas, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence - Mat - Max, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - Mc, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence - Me, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence - Mi - Mof, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence - Moh - My, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence - N, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - O, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence - Pa - Ph, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence - Pi - Q, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - General correspondence R-Z, 1895-1921 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Ra - Re, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence - Rh - Ri, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence - Ro, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence - Ru - Ry, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence - Sa, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence - Sch, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence - Se, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence - Sh, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence - Si - Sp, 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Forestry Related Materials, 1885-1933
  - Various addresses and papers, 1885-1900 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes one report addressed to the Adirondack League Club re: cutting on Club land and forest policy
  - Various addresses and papers, 1885-1900 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Includes one speech on the trees of Buffalo, conservation, forest management and "What interest has the farmers in forestry and the Adirondack problem"
  - Various addresses and papers on forestry policy, forestry propaganda, and farmers and forestry, 1885-1900 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Various addresses and papers on forestry in Russia and Alaska, the public and forestry, forest reservations, 1885-1900 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Also includes drafts for "The Forest as a Condition"
  - Correspondence with the New York Botanical Garden regarding Cuba Hardwood Company, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Various publications and reports on U.S. forestry policy, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Report on Township 26, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - University of Toronto Faculty of Forestry correspondence, 1914-1920 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1914-1920 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Department of Agriculture, Forestry Division correspondence predominantly with Office of the Secretary, 1887-1895 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with German colleagues, 1886-1915 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 3 photos of Axton forest, article in "Cornell Daily Sun" re: Fernow and "Journal of Forestry" containing article re: Fernow, 1902-1923 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Articles mainly regarding Fernow, 1897-1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letters from brother-in-law John Reynolds, 1886-1895 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letters from William Bruce King, 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Letters from sons Edward and Fritz, and daughter Rose, 1909-1911 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Records re: naturalization, 1877-1883 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re: Axton Forest, 1919-1921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Intimate History of the Rise and Fall of the New York College of Forestry at Cornell University, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence regarding closing of College of Forestry, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with tree nurseries regarding the purchase of seeds and seedlings for the College, Feb/Mar '94 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Record of planting and nursery work at the Axton Forest, 1899-1900 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Comments on Axton Plantations by Dr. Fernow, records of plantings and observations of Axton Sample Plots, 1919-1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "History of the Constitutional Amendment (Article VII, section 7) of the College Forest Experiment," by Dr. Fernow, notes and reports on the Axton Forest, 1900-1919 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Map of Cornell College Forest and correspondence re: Axton plantations, 1919-1933 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, plot surveys, and one map regarding Axton Forest, 1906-1932 (Box 3, Folder 20)